豪斯
House?
天啊
Oh! My God!
你搞什么鬼
What the hell?
抓到你了
Gotcha.
你起个大早
Did you actually wake up early
然后躲在床底下
and hide under the bed
就为了吓我一跳吗
just to scare the crap outta me?
还定了个闹钟什么的
Set an alarm and everything.
真像是在跟小学生谈恋爱
It's like dating a ten-year-old.
天呀  我希望不是
God, I hope not.
既然  我们都在地上了
Now that we're down here...
再等一下
Hold that thought.
不是吧
Seriously?
我要去尿尿
I have to pee.
我等着
I'll wait.
我拿了本书
I brought a book.
之前我不知道你闹钟定的几点
I didn't know what time your alarm was set for.
豪斯
House?
你可以把床下这片地方租出去的
You know, you can rent this space out down here.
这要在日本可是一个豪华的
In Japan, that would be like a deluxe--
豪斯  闭嘴
House, shut up.
我的尿液里有血
There's blood in my urine.
你们真的没必要来这里的
You really don't have to be here.
你是我女朋友  我要给你打气
You're my girlfriend. I'm being supportive.
我主要是指他们
I'm mainly talking about them.
既然基本可以肯定
Well, given that there's almost certainly
你没什么事
nothing wrong with you,
而我的病人又肯定有什么事
and my patient definitely has something wrong with him--
连一小时都撑不下去吗
That can't wait an hour?
恐怕不能
'Fraid not.
他
He's...
奇斯
Chase.
十六岁  男性
16-year-old male spit up blood
在一场小型篮球赛中吐血
during a pick-up basketball game.
急诊室在他的肺和胃肠道里
E.R. couldn't find the source in his lungs
均未发现出血点
or GI tract.
听到没  很严重的
See? Serious.
可能是脉管炎  支气管扩张
Could be vasculitis, bronchiectasis,
吸入颗粒物
inhaled particles.
会不会是肠道血管发育异常
What about angiodysplasia?
你们弄完我就可以开始了
Ready when you are...
让他们出去
Get them outta here.
我的尿道可不是供大众娱乐的
My urethra is not for public entertainment.
可它是好"道"相邻啊
But it is a good-time adjacent.
喂这孩子一个微型摄像机
Feed the kid a camera.
检查他是否肠血管发育异常
Check his got for angiodysplasia.
好了  往下坐一点
All right. If you could scoot down.
我丢了一块表
Hey, I'm, uh, I'm missing a watch.
-能不能帮我留意一下  -闭嘴
- So can you keep your eyes open while-- - Okay!
你也出去
You too.
这个小摄像机
This little camera
能将图像传送到数据记录器
transmits images to the data recorder
这样我们就能知道
so we can see
你的胃肠道里
if you've got any vascular malformations
是否有血管畸形
in your GI tract.
你的病例上显示
Your records show
去年你的体重减轻了一些
you've lost some weight over the past year.
-是有意要减肥吗  -不算是
- Was that intentional? - Not really.
自从他退出游泳队之后  食量就变小了
Well, he's been eating less since he quit the swim team.
你必须得早起去参加游泳训练
You have to get up early for swim.
一点乐趣都没有了
It wasn't fun anymore.
我要跟你们儿子谈谈他的性行为
I need to talk to your son about sexual activity.
通常来讲  为了不让大家觉得尴尬
Generally, it's less embarrassing for everyone--
我们这就出去
We're leaving.
其实  我只有过
Actually, I've only--
你这样自残有多久了
How long have you been cutting yourself?
那些伤是因为一次玩滑板失误造成的
Those are from a layback grind that went wrong.
从滑板上摔下来直接撞到栅栏上了
Came off my skateboard straight into a fence.
所以  不承认自残
So...no to cutting
但是承认饮食和作息习惯的改变
but yes to appetite and sleep changes,
并且放弃了过去喜欢做的事
and you quit something you used to enjoy.
你抑郁多久了
How long have you been depressed?
显像结果表明
Imaging showed no sign
上消化道没问题
of upper GI issues.
但那孩子承认了自己抑郁
But the kid did admit to being depressed
并且通过吸食大麻来释放压力
and to smoking pot to take the edge off.
你对自己非常满意  是不是
You are very pleased with yourself, aren't you?
他的大麻里可能混有甲醛或者铅
His marijuana could be laced with formaldehyde or lead,
这会导致肺出血
which could cause a pulmonary hemorrhage
从而出现吐血的症状
which could make him spit up blood.
是  没错  我是对自己很满意
Yes. Yes, I am.
我觉得我做得很不错
I thought it was a good catch.
测试铅水平  五升静脉注射
Run a lead level and push 5 liters IV fluid.
给你另一个佣人也来点小费吧  没事的
Feel free to tip your other server.
膀胱镜检查结果没问题
Cystoscopy was clean.
细胞病理检验正常
Cytopathology was normal.
你怎么会有我的检查报告
Why do you have my lab results?
我没有
I don't.
如果我有  我就知道你没事了
If I did, I'd know you were fine.
除非是我的肾出血
Unless the blood came from my kidneys.
得了吧  你那疑神疑鬼的老妈
Come on. Your hypochondriac mom
上个月差点被死神带走
had a brush with mortality last month,
你比平时多点担心
and it's understandable that you're worrying
也是人之常情
more than usual,
担心自己会变成她
worrying that you might turn into her.
你说对了
You're right.
不同的是  我没事
Odds are, this is nothing.
十点餐厅见
Meet me in the cafeteria in ten.
你会看到一个写着你名字的玉米热狗肠
There'll be a corn dog with your name on it.
我是说真的玉米热狗肠
I mean an actual corn dog.
他们把油炸锅修好了
They fixed the deep fryer.
我要预约一次超声波检查
I need to schedule an ultrasound.
我爸爸还很冷静
My dad's head's still in one piece,
所以我猜你没跟他说大麻的事
so I'm guessing you didn't mention the pot.
你都跟他说什么了
What'd you tell him?
实话  你患有
The truth. You had a...
轻微的化学元素中毒
minor chemical exposure,
我们也不能百分百确定是如何发生的
and we can't be 100% sure how it happened.
谢谢你帮我打掩护
Thanks for covering.
我知道十六岁是什么样的
I know what it's like to be 16.
你也知道抑郁是什么样的
You also know what it's like to be depressed.
才几分钟你就看出了我的问题
You figured out my deal after only a few minutes,
我却糊弄了我爸妈和朋友几个月了
but I been fooling my friends and parents for months.
我的工作就是发现问题
It's my job to notice things.
也许和你的父母聊聊能有所好转
Maybe talking to your parents would make things better.
我试过了
I've tried.
他们只是认为我不开心而已
They take it personally that I'm not happy,
之后就变成我还得哄他们高兴
and then I end up having to make them feel better.
他们不理解我
They don't get me.
没有人理解我
No one does.
在医学院时  似乎所有人
In med school, it seemed like
都能很好的应对压力
everybody else could handle the pressure.
我却不能
I couldn't.
最后只得以自残告终
I ended up hurting myself.
这是我做过最蠢的事
Stupidest thing I've ever done.
你眼内有红色斑点
You've got red spots in your eyes.
之前没有的
They weren't there before.
你皮肤不错
You have nice skin.
谢谢  说什么呢
Thank you. Shut up!
不好意思
Sorry.
我只是觉得如果不评论一下太不礼貌了
Just thought it would be rude not to comment.
把我当一般病人就行
Just treat me like any other patient.
没错
Right.
你是在吸气收小腹吗
Are you sucking in your stomach?
没有
No.
赶紧在我憋昏过去之前弄完
Hurry up before I pass out.
威尔森
Wilson?
超声波不是最可靠的
Ultrasound isn't definitive.
我们需要做其它测试才能
We should run other tests before--
别来医生那一套  告诉我你看到了什么
Stop talking like a doctor and tell me what you see.
你的肾里有个团块
There's a mass in your kidney.
我们还是不知道瑞安为什么会咳血
We still don't know why Ryan coughed blood,
现在他眼底又有少量出血
and now he's got small hemorrhages in his eyes.
听上去像后天获得性凝血病变
Sounds like an acquired coagulapathy
这可能有多种鉴别诊断
which gives us a pretty wide differential.
如果考虑到抑郁
It gets a lot narrower
范围就能大大缩小了
if we factor in his depression.
别这样
Oh, don't do that!
情绪波动可能是生理疾病导致的症状
Mood swings can be a symptom of physiological illness.
没跟你说话
I'm not talking to you.
情绪波动也可能是青春期
Mood swings are also a symptom of adolescence
伴随摇滚乐和手淫出现的症状
along with emo music and masturbation.
更重要的是  他的体重减少
More importantly, his weight loss
以及睡眠问题从一年前就开始了
and sleeping issues started a year ago.
感染最有可能
Infection makes the most sense.
他在学校打篮球  在更衣室洗澡
He shoots hoops at school, showers in the locker room.
-我觉得是葡萄球菌感染  -该死
- I'm thinking staph. - Damn!
你不认为
You don't think--
没跟你说话
Not talking to you!
-卡迪没事吧  -她没事
- Everything okay with Cuddy? - She's fine.
只不过她听风就是雨
She's just too stupid to accept it.
用青霉素治疗葡萄球菌感染
Start him on nafcillin for staph.
那些都在
All that's in the, uh,
第一银行的保险柜里
First Mutual safety deposit box.
退休金
The retirement accounts--
一个不称职的非洲猩猩做的超声波检查
You're freaking out because of one ultrasound
就能把你吓成这样
performed by an incompetent bonobo monkey.
我还坐在这镇定的
As demonstrated by my sitting here calmly
处理事务正好佐证了你的话
going about my business.
叫律师来起草遗嘱
Calling a lawyer, drafting a will!
好吧  我...
Okay. I-I...
偷看了你网上的日程安排
hacked into your online schedule.
检查总能查出点什么
Look, tests always show something.
你肾里的团块可能只是复合囊肿
A mass in your kidney could be a complex cyst.
-很可能是良性的  -我是单身母亲
- It could be benign. - I'm a single mom.
我需要建立信托基金  指定监护人
I need to set up a trust, appoint a guardian.
我以前没做才是太傻了
It's silly that I haven't done it before now.
但你现在做是因为你觉得你病了
But you're doing it now because you think you're sick.
你至少可以等到下午的活检结果
The freaking out can at least wait
出来以后再开始惊慌失措
until after the biopsy this afternoon.
活检结果明天才会出来
The biopsy's not till tomorrow.
已经是预约的第一个了
It's the first opening in the schedule.
对于医院院长
For the dean of medicine,
第一个就意味着...
the first opening in the schedule is...
看  就是现在
Oh, look! Now.
我的担忧并不比其他人的更重要
My worry isn't any more important than anyone else's.
实际上  就要比别人重要
Actually, it is.
但我没病  对吧
But I'm not sick, right?
说得好
Good point.
我要我的货  混蛋
I want my stuff, asshat.
我跟你说过了  兄弟  货不在这里
I told you, man, I don't have it here.
伙计们
Guys.
一切都还好吗
Everything okay?
我这就走
On my way out.
回头见
I'll see you later.
你想  告诉我这是怎么回事吗
You wanna... tell me what's going on?
我朋友去换领癫痫药时
My friend gave me some leftover klonopin he had
给了我一些多余的克诺平[抗焦虑药]
when he switched his seizure meds.
我八十块卖给了洛依德·瑞吉
I sold them to Roid Rage for 80 bucks,
但在交货前我就住进来了
but I landed in here before I could deliver,
现在他该废了我了
and now he's gonna rip my arms off.
你多久卖一次药
How often do you sell drugs?
仅此一次
It was a one-time thing.
我需要钱  手里又有药
I needed the cash, I had the pills,
我就琢磨  何乐而不为呢
so I thought, "Why not?"
这主意糟透了
It was a bad idea.
药在我家
The pills are at my house.
我可以让朋友去拿来
I could have a friend go get them.
把钱还给那痞子
Give the thug his money back.
仅此一次
One time only.
我是说  如果你觉得这样可以的话
I mean, if you're okay with this.
你自己还有三个孩子
You have three kids of your own.
这还用问吗
It's not even a question.
我当然愿意当瑞秋的监护人
Of course I'll be Rachel's guardian.
豪斯对这没意见吗
And House is cool with this?
我是说  你们
I mean, you guys...
我们在一起才几个月
We've only been together a few months.
感觉上已经很久了
Hmm. Seems like a lot longer.
可能是因为你已经
Probably because you've been talking
谈论他有十年了
about him for ten years.
我说的谈论是指
And by talking, I mean ranting about
你一直嚷嚷要用订书机
wanting to smash his teeth in
把这混蛋的牙打碎
with a stapler for being such a jerk.
人是会变的
People change.
我来开
I'll get it.
最好是她
That better be her!
瑞秋·卡迪
Rachel Cuddy,
你半小时前就该回家了
you were supposed to be home half an hour ago.
别怪我  是他
Don't blame me-- he's the one
不愿意闯红灯的
who wouldn't run any red lights.
这孩子的嘴
Mouth on that kid
能让梅尔·吉布森变成尼尔森·曼德拉
makes Mel Gibson sound like Nelson Mandela.
她这都从哪学的
Where'd she learn that?
我不知道你为啥在这儿
I don't know why you're here,
不过不是我干的
but I didn't do it.
有什么问题吗  警官
What's the problem, officer?
她在商场里偷东西
She was shoplifting down at the mall.
你们俩谁是这女孩的父亲
Are either of you this girl's father?
都不是  不过自打她妈死了以后
Nope. But since her mom died,
她倒成了我最好的免税理由
she's my favorite tax write-off.
警官  我保证下不为例
Officer, you have my word it won't happen again.
因为下次
'Cause next time...
她绝不会再被抓着了
she won't get caught!
没什么大不了的
It's no big deal.
你能这么想挺好
Good for you.
你本可以认为他是个毒贩子
You could have just assumed he was a drug dealer,
但你相信了他的话
but you took his word for it.
真高兴终于看到这里有人
It's nice to finally see someone
依然对人性存有一丝信心了
have a little faith in humanity around here.
你为什么要这么做
Why would you do that?
-瑞安  你在里边还好吧  -我不知道
- Ryan, you okay in there?  - I'm not sure.
我想我刚尿血了
I think I just peed blood.
看来尿血成了新风潮了
Looks like peeing blood is the new black.
头晚使用抗生素第二天尿血
Peeing blood after a night on antibiotics
说明可以确定不是感染了
means we can move on from infections.
窥镜检查没发现他膀胱内出血
Scoping showed no sign of a bleed in his bladder,
说明是肾有问题
which points to a kidney problem.
可能是什么团块
Probably some kinda mass.
肾脏团块解释不了咳血
Kidney mass wouldn't explain the coughing blood
和眼内的血点
or the hemorrhages.
但是  抗磷脂综合征
Antiphospholipid syndrome, on the other hand...
靠点谱  但也不能排除有团块
Makes sense. But doesn't rule out a mass.
你觉得是癌症吗
You think it's cancer?
团块不一定是癌症
Mass doesn't have to be cancer.
可能是肾脏水肿
Could be renal hematoma.
但病人没有
But the patient doesn't have
-任何腹部创伤  -他
- any other abdominal trauma. - He's...
没在说这个病人
not talking about the patient.
卡迪肾脏有个团块吗
Cuddy has a mass on her kidney?
可能只是个复合囊肿
It's probably just a complex cyst
或者是血管瘤
or angiomyolipoma.
是个团块  又不是个谜
It's a mass, not a mystery.
他们会做活检的  然后就有答案了
They'll do the biopsy, then you'll have your answer.
只是  得再等等
Just...have to wait.
病人承认吸过大麻
Patient admitted to using pot.
谁知道他还吸过什么
Who knows what else he's doing.
这可能是海洛因相关性肾病
This could be a heroin-induced nephropathy.
我以为你相信这孩子的
I thought you trusted this kid.
直到你指出我的做法很贴心
And then you pointed out how sweet that was.
如果是海洛因  他会有戒断反应
If it were heroin, he'd be going through withdrawal.
抗磷脂综合征更合适
Antiphospholipid syndrome's a better fit.
给病人用血浆除去法
Start the patient on plasmapheresis.
他做检查的时候
While he's doing that,
我能去搜查他家里有没有毒品吗
can I at least search his house for drugs?
还用问吗
Have I ever said no to that question?
你在这干什么呢
What are you doing here?
吃馅饼大赛
Pie-eating contest.
一小时后卡迪就要进行活检了
Cuddy's biopsy is in an hour.
你现在应该陪着她
You should be keeping her company.
好吧  你担心你们的关系
Okay. You've been worried that your relationship
会影响你的诊断
is getting in the way of your diagnoses,
所以你是在保护你的病人
you're protecting your patient.
要么是这样  要么你就是个混蛋
Either that or... you're an ass.
我选三  因为我讨厌死亡的气味
Three--I hate the smell of death.
卡迪患肾细胞癌的几率
The chances of Cuddy having renal cell carcinoma--
我说的是咱俩的友谊
I'm talking about our relationship.
她需要支持和安慰
She needs support and comfort,
都是我出了名搞不定的
both things that I famously suck at.
这样会不可避免地导致
This will inevitably lead to--
你知道怎么才能进步吗  练习
You know what's good for that? Practice.
去做  我不知道  一次
Doing it--I don't know-- once?
在知道结果以前
I'm not gonna act like there's a crisis
我才不会装得煞有介事
before we know there is one.
没有证据表明她有事
There's no proof there's anything wrong with her.
也没有证据说明她被
There's no proof she's being stalked
忍者松鼠跟踪
by ninja squirrels either,
但如果她害怕的话
but if she's scared of them...
作为她的男友  你有义务要想法子
as her boyfriend, it's your job to figure out
让她好受些
how to help her feel better.
你说得对
You're right.
豪斯让我来陪陪你
House told me to keep you company.
护士让我给你吃抗生素
Nurse told me to give you antibiotics.
告诉豪斯我没事
Tell House I'm fine.
汤姆·克鲁斯结婚了
Tom Cruise got married.
你想让我引用哥多林前书的桥段吗
Do you want me to quote from First Corinthians?
[哥多林前书是圣经全书第46本书]
[也是使徒保罗为哥林多人所写的第一封书信]
-因为我可以哦  -作为一个犹太人
- 'Cause I can do that. - As a Jew,
我不得不谢绝你的提议
I'm gonna have to decline that offer.
不知道你会错过什么吧
Don't know what you're missing.
圣保罗可是很在行呢
St. Paul was really on his game.
他最终会来的
He'll show up eventually.
其实你都不信自己说的话
You don't actually believe that.
但我相信
But I do.
这么多年
All these years,
他十五分钟不来骚扰我一下
He's never stopped trying to annoy me
都忍不住
for more than 15 minutes.
而他现在甚至都不敢进来
And now he can't even walk into the room.
有爱就有希望
Love hopes all things.
你和这孩子到底怎么回事
What is it with you and this kid?
他在苦海里挣扎
He's doggy paddling in a sea of misery.
我记得那是什么感觉
I remember what it's like.
这段回忆离你有多远
How far did you have to reach back for that memory,
昨晚吗
last night?
有时我听到你半夜三点
Sometimes I hear you in the living room
在客厅里看电视
watching TV at 3:00 a.m.
那是BBC播放经典《神秘医生》的时间
That's when classic Dr. Who comes on the BBC.
是啊  要是他们有个设备
Yeah. If only they had some device
能让你把节目录下来
that allowed you to record them
回头再看就好了
and watch them another time.
我是说...
I'm just saying...
我不觉得治好这孩子你就没事了
I don't think fixing this kid is gonna fix you.
咋了
Yep?
我们马上回去
We're on our way back.
病人右臂完全失去知觉了
Our patient lost all feeling in his right arm.
看这个
Look at this.
奇斯
Chase?
卡迪怎么样了
How'd it go with Cuddy?
奇斯
Chase?
好在我带了我的斧头拐杖来
Good thing I brought my ax cane.
豪斯  救命
House...help me!
我来了
I'm coming!
豪斯  快啊
House...please!
看来同伴不少啊
It looks like we got company.
豪斯
House!
不
No!
你没事吧
Are you okay?
我就是睡着了
I was sleeping.
能有什么事
What could go wrong?
病人正用着类固醇
Patient lost feeling in his arm
他的胳膊失去了知觉  排除了自体免疫疾病
while on steroids-- rules out autoimmune.
那是什么会引起出血  肾功能障碍
So what causes bleeding, kidney problems,
以及单侧肢体麻痹呢
and unilateral numbness?
卡迪的肾脏活检
And a complete absence of any record
没留下任何记录
of Cuddy's kidney biopsy.
她肯定用了化名
She must have put it under a false name
这样我就没法去催结果了
so I couldn't rush the results.
如果我们反过来思考
What if we had it backwards
这也许不是出血问题  而是凝血问题
and it's not a bleeding problem, it's a clotting problem?
最近两天  没有为做肾脏活检
There's no patient file created in the last two days
而建立的新病例
for anyone having that procedure.
她把病例的日期提前了吗
She backdated the file?
很聪明的办法
That's very clever.
别多管闲事  她是我的
Hands off. She's mine.
血栓可以解释全部症状
Clots could explain everything
包括肢体麻痹
including the numbness.
我们可以做脑部血管造影
We should do an angiogram of his brain,
看能不能找到血栓
see if we can find it.
豪斯
House.
我们也很担心
We're worried too.
好感人呀
How sweet.
我不担心
I'm not worried.
我就是想快点得到结果
I just wanna get the results
这样她就不用担心了
so she can stop worrying.
-但同时  -去做血管造影
- Okay, but in the meantime-- - Do an angiogram.
你们两个去病理科看看卡迪的切片
You two go to pathology and look at Cuddy's slides.
你刚才还说不知道哪个切片是她的
You just said you didn't know which sample was hers.
我猜你们只能把所有的切片都看了
I guess you're gonna have to look at them all.
更大的问题是  陶博在搞什么
Bigger question-- what's the deal with Taub?
豪斯心不在焉  没注意到你心不在焉
Just because House is too distracted
并不意味着我们也注意不到
to notice your distraction doesn't mean we didn't.
血栓  血管造影  我很专心
Clots, angiograms-- I'm focused.
那小孩把班级纪念册上一半同学的脸都涂黑了
The kid scratched out the faces of half his class.
你不觉得这是个问题吗
You don't think that's a problem?
这不是我们的问题
It's not our problem.
这怎么就算个问题了
Why is it anyone's problem?
我曾经在脑海里把十年级的几何老师
I violently executed my tenth grade geometry teacher
用异常残酷的方法处死过五次
about five different ways in my mind.
我从来没想过要去杀人
I didn't want to kill anybody.
我只想把他们关在地下室里慢慢折磨他们
I just wanted to torture them slowly in my basement,
最好是用酸
preferably with acid.
你们就从来没想过要怎么蹂躏豪斯吗
You guys ever think about what you might to do House?
也许这没什么大不了的
Maybe it's no big deal.
如果是  问题就大了
Unless it is.
有没有人想枪杀豪斯的
Someone shot house?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
吃馅饼比赛
Pie-eating contest.
我本来想让奇斯
I was going to send Chase
来告诉你  你现在最该做的事情是什么
to tell you what the obvious right thing to do here is,
但我又想到
but then I realized...
如果你愚蠢到无法看出那样做有多傻的话
if you were too stupid to know how stupid that was,
我的讽刺就变成对牛弹琴了
you might miss the irony.
你得去陪她
You have to be with her.
是的  我知道
Yeah. I get it.
她因为一个虚无缥缈的问题
She needs artificial support
需要我矫揉造作的支持
for an artificial problem.
她很好  奇斯做得很不错
She's fine. Chase did an excellent job.
她又不跟奇斯上床
She doesn't sleep with Chase.
这我们就不知道了
We don't know that.
我正在这里吃馅饼呢
Eating pie in here.
豪斯
House...
我不会再跟你讲第三遍
I'm not gonna tell you a third time.
这次千万别搞砸
Do not screw this up.
我真不想替你收拾残局
Because I really don't wanna clean up the mess.
他在说馅饼
He's referring to the pie.
做肾脏活检的有十四位病人
14 patients with kidney biopsies.
我对照了他们尿检的结果
I tabulated them against their urinalysis results.
六名男性  三位糖尿病患者
Six men, three diabetics,
一名轻链沉积病患者  一个小孩  两位老人
one LCDD, one kid, two seniors,
最后剩下的  一个卡迪
and by default, one...Cuddy.
活检的结果是无法确定
Uh...the biopsy was inconclusive.
团块位于肾脏中心
The mass is near the center of her kidney.
他们没能取到合适的样体
They couldn't get a readable sample.
也就是说必须切除团块
Means they'll have to remove the mass
才能判断是不是癌症
to know if it's cancer or not.
按照病例的记载
The file says
他们现在正在做影像学检查
they're doing some imaging now,
好让主刀医生对卡迪的情况
give the surgeon a better idea
有更充分的了解
of what he's dealing with.
我们可以叫比萨吗
Can we order pizza?
冰箱里什么都没有了
There's nothing in the fridge.
至少现在什么都没有了
At least not anymore.
病人怎么样了
What's happening with the patient?
血管造影在大脑中动脉
Angio showed a clot
的一个分支里发现了一个凝血块
in a branch of his middle cerebral artery.
已经开始给他用链激酶溶栓了
Started him on streptokinase to break it up.
然而  也许我们应该先玩几轮
Although...maybe we should have just played a few rounds
野蛮逃脱2:复仇  这个游戏
of SavageScape 2: the revenge, because that's obviously
显然是让某人心情好起来的最佳办法
the best way to make someone feel better.
再学威尔森  你的脸就再也变不回来了
You keep talking like Wilson, your face will freeze like that.
无论你觉得去陪她会有多痛苦
Look, however bad you think you're gonna be in that room,
不去只会更痛苦
not being in the room is worse.
等她跟你分手了
When she breaks up with you...
才轮到你独自一人打游戏
you're playing by yourself.
亲爱的  我回来了
Honey, I'm home.
真准时  焖肉刚刚做好
Just in time. Pot roast is ready.
闻起来真香
Smells wonderful!
我治好了我所有的病人
I cured all my patients,
所以我就下班回家陪瑞秋
so I came home to spend time with Rachel.
你今天过得怎么样
And how was your day today?
棒极了  妈妈
It was great, ma!
我拼写考试得了满分
I got 100% on my spelling test
法学院入学考试考了170分
and 170 on my LSATs!
法学院入学考试  你才八岁呀
Your LSATs? You're eight years old.
我们可是一起学习的
We've been studying together.
那原本应该是个惊喜
It was supposed to be a surprise.
不管怎么样  那真是太好了
Well, that's wonderful.
我认为瑞秋
I think Rachel
应该获得奖赏
deserves a treat.
不了  谢谢爸爸
No, thanks, daddy.
一会儿该吃不下饭了
It might spoil my appetite.
会是谁啊
Well, who could that be?
您的蛋糕  豪斯夫人
Delivery for you, Mrs. House.
29岁生日快乐
Happy 29th birthday.
我才不是29岁呢
I'm not 29!
你的腿不瘸了
You're not limping.
不可能啊
This isn't possible.
这一切都不可能
None of this is possible.
有梦就有可能
Girl can dream.
你是砂糖用完了吗
You run out of sugar?
我拿到了你今天的扫描结果
Got your scans back from today.
喂
Yeah.
好的
Okay.
怎么了
What's going on?
片子显示病变的增强显影
Imaging shows enhancing masses
在卡迪的多个肺叶里扩散
across multiple lobes of Cuddy's lungs.
那是肾癌转移的表现
That's what kidney cancer looks like when it metastasizes.
她没救了
She's dead.
怎样  窝囊废
What's up, losers?
希望你们还活得自在
I hope you're enjoying being alive.
今天的课程  自然选择
Today's lesson: natural selection.
瑰丽的生态国度  造就了今天的我们
Excellent system. Made us who we are today.
但我们发明了安全带和便利店
But then we invented seat belts and grocery stores,
让白痴和废物也能活下来
things that keep idiots and weaklings alive.
老实说
And let's be honest.
你们中的大多数没资格活着
Most of you don't really deserve it.
向自然法则致敬
Here's to the natural order.
太棒了
Yes!
从他闪存盘拷过来的
Copied from his flash drive.
我要报警吗
Do I go to the cops?
报吧  "警官  我要举报一桩袭击案
Yes. "Officer, I'd like to report an assault.
受害者是一堆树叶"
The victim was a pile of leaves."
会升级的
It goes on.
他都说想炸了学校
He talks about bombing his school.
你私闯住宅  偷了他的闪存盘
Which you know because you stole his flash drive
所以你才发现这些
and broke into his house.
这出戏你要怎么演
How's that gonna play?
链激酶对瑞安无效
Ryan's not responding to streptokinase.
在损伤变得不可修复之前
We don't have very long before the damage
我们没多少时间了
becomes irreversible.
我们要么加大用药剂量
So we either up his dosage
要么就到他脑袋里取出血栓
or go into his head and get the clot out.
-豪斯人呢  -但愿他和卡迪在一起
- Where's House? - Hopefully with Cuddy.
她刚得知些不幸的消息
She did just get some pretty awful news.
我打电话问过了
I called her.
她也不知道他在哪里
She doesn't know where he is either.
见过豪斯吗
Have you seen House?
没有
No.
昨晚接完你电话  他就离开我家了
He left my place last night after you called.
今天没人见过他
No one's seen him today.
知道他可能去哪里吗
Any idea where he'd be?
不知道
No.
你都  不担心他吗
And you're not... worried about that?
他不善于处理坏消息
He's not good with bad news.
不  我担心
Yes. I'm worried.
但现在豪斯不是重点  卡迪才是
But this isn't about House. It's about Cuddy.
她才是有可能会死的那个
She's the one who could be dying,
而他又想把自己变成主角
and he's trying to make this about himself.
我不打算陪他玩
I'm not playing.
好吧
Okay...
她仍相信他会出现
She still believes he'll show up.
他要么自己想通
He'll either get over himself
回来扮演好为人男友的角色
and be who she needs him to be
要么继续逃避
or he won't.
我们想做个血栓清除术
We'd like to do an embolectomy.
用螺旋形导丝沿血管进入瑞安的大脑中动脉
We'll run a corkscrew-shaped instrument into Ryan's brain
取出血栓
and pull the clot out.
好吧
Okay.
你们和他谈过了吗
Have you talked to him about it?
是的  但我想和你们单独谈谈
Yes. But I wanted to see you alone.
我看了些瑞安几周前拍的视频
I saw some vides that Ryan made a few weeks ago.
片中他在引爆炸药管
He's blowing up pipe bombs
恐吓他学校的人
and threatening people in his school.
哦  天啊
Oh, god!
他可能只是瞎捣蛋
He was probably just messing around.
我儿子不会伤害任何人的
Our son wouldn't hurt anybody.
我不那么确定
I'm not so sure.
我知道这看起来很糟
I know this looks bad,
不过瑞安是好孩子
but Ryan's a good kid.
进高中后的这两年
He's had a rough couple years
他是过得不好
since he started high school,
不过我真的相信他会缓过来
but I really think he'll come out of it.
-他需要帮助  -也许是
- He needs help. - Maybe he does,
但这要是传出去  他会被停学
but if this gets out, he'll be suspended,
也许被开除
maybe expelled.
你能不能先专注于救他的命
How about you focus on keeping him alive?
你会怎么做
What are you gonna do?
你觉得我该怎么做
What do you think I should do?
切  哼
Pssh. Ha.
我说出来  你好唱反调么
So you can do the opposite?
全国上下许多小孩都在做
There are kids all over the country
愚蠢至极  有暴力倾向的事
doing dumb, potentially violent things,
可真正演变为犯罪杀人的
but the percentage of them who would actually kill anybody
却没几个
is miniscule.
所以我该置若罔闻
So I shouldn't do anything.
呃  虽然几率很低
Mm...while the odds are low,
一旦放虎归山  可能  后患无穷
the fallout could be... huge.
伤及数十甚至数百条生命
Tens or even hundreds of lives.
所以我该报警检举
So I should call the cops.
当然  过分纠结于给这事定性
Of course, over-identification with the subject
容易歪曲计算结果  朝未雨绸缪的方向发展
could skew the calculation towards being extra-protective.
又或者
Or alternatively--
你说的全是废话
You suck at this.
应该怪统计学
Hate the statistics...
别迁怒统计员
Not the statistician.
再加点显影剂
Give me a little more dye.
血栓在这
There's the clot.
你刚碰到  它就溶解了
It just disintegrated when you touched it.
那是什么东西
What was that thing?
我想到个绝佳去处
I got a great idea where we should go.
我不想听
I don't want to hear it.
你会喜欢的
You're gonna love it.
去澳大利亚最好
Australia's finest.
纽瓦克有个超赞的卡拉OK酒吧
There's a great karaoke bar in Newark--
我讨厌卡拉OK
I hate karaoke.
他们有所有澳洲歌手
They got every-- every song
的所有  每一首歌曲
by every Aussie artist.
午夜之油  工作者合唱团
Midnight Oil, Men at Work,
奥莉维亚·纽顿·约翰[女歌手]
Olivia Newton John.
我物理可不行[指牛顿]
I do a mean version of physical.
而且烤虾棒极了
And the barbecue shrimp is amazing.
薯条怎么样
What about the fries?
味美香咸
Hot and salty and delicious.
一谈论食物我就饿了
Talking about food made me hungry.
在我其它的梦里你吃的是糖
You had candy in my other dreams.
说明你工作压力太大了
Means you're stressed at work.
所有的梦境都意味着你工作压力太大了
All dream symbols mean you're stressed at work.
要不就是阉割焦虑症
Or castration anxiety.
得了吧
No.
我还指望
I was hoping...
你能想出个办法来应对现在的情况
You'd figure out a way to handle all this.
或许你根本不能  因为你还是那么孩子气
Maybe you can't because you're still a child.
我能做得更好
I can do better.
也许为时已晚了
Might be too late.
豪斯
House!
我早该过来陪你的
I should have been here.
抱歉
Sorry.
我知道你会来的
I knew you'd come.
那到底是什么东西
What was that thing,
为什么它会在手术中途溶解了呢
and why did it just dissolve in the middle of surgery?
为什么他的肝脏正要停止工作呢
Why is his liver shutting down?
他脑袋里的那个东西消失了
That thing in his brain goes away,
那小孩却陷入了昏迷
the kid slips into a coma.
我们可以用乳果糖来治疗
We started him on Lactulose,
但是从他肝功能下降的速度来看
but at the rate his liver function is declining,
他只能活一天了
he'll be dead in a day.
我们要呼豪斯吗
Should we page House?
他正忙着呢
He's busy.
豪斯帮不上她一星半点的忙
House can't do anything for her now.
我们需要他  按他的逻辑
We need him! By his own logic--
病人的巴比妥和对乙酰氨基酚血检结果
Patient's blood tests were negative
都呈阴性
for Barbiturates or Acetaminophen.
他没有采用高蛋白节食法
He's not on a high protein diet.
豪斯在她奄奄一息之前就已经
House couldn't concentrate on the case
无法集中精神在这病例上了
before she was dying.
你觉得他现在就能关注这个病例了吗
You think he's gonna get in the game now?
要是你没撑下来
If you don't make it,
我保证至少一个月不和别人睡
I won't sleep with anyone for at least a month.
两个月吧
Make it two.
臭婆娘
Bitch.
急性间歇性血卟啉病会导致尿毒症
A.I.P. can cause uremia,
增加肝脏负担
tank the liver.
那会导致腹部痉挛  而不是腹部出血
It causes abdominal cramping, not abdominal bleeding.
那岩藻糖苷病就对了吗
Oh, because fucosidosis was such a brilliant idea?
同志们
Guys!
二型瓜氨酸血症符合症状
Type 2 citrullinemia fits.
但没有高脂血症和
There are no signs of hyperlipidemia
胰腺炎的迹象
or pancreatitis.
这两项症状会潜伏很多年才发作
Those can take years to emerge.
这是我们得出的最靠谱的结果
Closest we've gotten.
开始用四型苯甲酸钠治疗
Start him on IV Sodium Benzoate.
来降低他血液里氨的含量
To reduce the ammonia levels in his blood.
做个瓜氨酸血症的基因测试
Run a genetic test for citrullinemia.
忘却你的烦恼*
*Forget your troubles
来寻找快乐吧*
*Come on, get happy
忘却你的烦恼*
*Forget your troubles
将你的担忧通通丢掉*
*You better chase all your cares away
喊声哈利路亚*
*Shout hallelujah
来寻找快乐吧*
*Come on, get happy
为审判日作好准备*
*Get ready for the judgment day
阳光灿烂  来寻找快乐吧*
*The sun is shining, come on, get happy
天主正等待牵起你的手*
*The lord is waiting to take your hand
喊声哈利路亚  来寻找快乐吧*
*Shout hallelujah, come on, get happy
我们正在前往  应许之地*
*We're goin' to the promised land
我们正在穿过河流*
*We're heading across the river
潮水洗刷你的罪行*
*Wash your sins in the tide
一切都是如此安详*
*It's all so peaceful
尽在世界的彼岸*
*On the other side
忘却你的烦恼  来寻找快乐吧*
*Forget your troubles, come on, get happy
将你的担忧通通丢掉*
*You better chase all your cares away
喊声哈利路亚  来寻找快乐吧*
*Shout hallelujah, come on, get happy
为审判日作好准备*
*Get ready for the judgment day
忘却你的烦恼  来寻找快乐吧*
*Forget your troubles, come on, get happy
将你的担忧通通丢掉*
*You better chase all your cares away
*Chase all your cares away
喊声哈利路亚*
*Shout hallelujah
来寻找快乐吧*
*Come on, get happy
准备好了吗*
*Get ready?
迎接*
*For the judgment
审判日*
*Day
寻找快乐  准备  准备*
*Get happy. Get ready. Get ready
寻找快乐  寻找快乐*
*Get happy. Get happy
准备  准备*
*Get ready, get ready
寻找快乐*
*Get happy
准备  快乐*
*Get ready! Happy!
准备*
*Get ready
寻找快乐*
*Get happy
忘却你的烦恼  来寻找快乐吧*
*Forget your troubles, come on, get happy
将你的担忧通通丢掉*
*You better chase your cares away
喊声哈利路亚  来寻找快乐吧*
*Shout hallelujah, come on, get happy
为审判日作好准备*
*Get ready for the judgment day
阳光灿烂  来寻找快乐吧*
*The sun is shining, come on, get happy
天主正等待牵起你的手*
*The lord is waiting to take your hand
喊声哈利路亚  来寻找快乐吧*
*Shout hallelujah, come on, get happy
为审判日作好准备*
*Get ready for the judgment day
忘却你的烦恼  来寻找快乐吧*
*Forget your troubles, come on, get happy
为审判日作好准备*
*Get ready for the judgment day
喊声哈利路亚*
*Shout hallelujah
来寻找快乐吧*
*Come on, get happy
为审判作好准备*
*Get ready for the judgment
*Ready for the judgment
为审判作好准备*
作好准备*
*Ready for the
猜猜谁没得癌症
Guess who doesn't have cancer?
我
Me.
还有你
Also you.
其实  你是肯定没有  我呢...
Actually, you for sure. Me...
豪斯
House.
你的肿瘤是良性的
Your tumor was benign.
是嗜酸细胞瘤
An oncocytoma.
已经切除了  你没事了
They cut it out. You'll be fine.
那我肺里的是什么
Then what was in my lungs?
排除癌症之后
Once they ruled out cancer,
我想起你妈抗生素过敏的事
I remembered that your mom was allergic to antibiotics.
就让他们给你验血
So I had them test your blood,
你的免疫球蛋白E都高到天上去了
and your IgE levels were through the roof.
肺部团块是过敏反应
Because the lung masses were an allergic reaction.
所以你一经停用抗生素
So now you're off the antibiotics,
肺应该会很快好起来
your lungs should clear right up.
我给你带了东西
I brought you something.
来跟你的肿瘤打个招呼
Say hello to your tumor.
等下
Wait.
我心里有很多事足以令我恐慌
There are so many things that I could be afraid of,
多数时候
and most of the time,
我能用重重屏障封住那些恐惧
I manage to lock them up behind doors.
可是我这一病
But this happens
所有屏障都崩坏了
all those doors just burst open.
又突然找到
You just figured something out
诊断灵感了是不是
about your patient, didn't you?
去吧  做你该做的
Go. Do what you do.
给他停药
Take him off the meds.
他是葡萄球菌感染
He's got a staph infection.
三天前你们给他治疗过葡萄球菌感染
You treated him for staph three days ago.
没有作用
It didn't work.
他体内已有的细菌起了反应
Bacteria already in his system responded.
一道屏障被击破  道道崩溃
Once a door's been busted open, more just keep coming.
他说的是脓肿
Oh! He's talking about an abscess.
我听得懂
I got that.
对乘虚而入者而言
For the cheap seats,
脓肿就是感染的奶油泡芙
an abscess is a gooey little cream puff of infection.
很可能就是在你的傲慢和
Probably burst when your little pride
杀人乐趣爆发时崩溃的
and homicidal joy took a hard foul.
这是好消息
It's good news.
前提是我们找到那道屏障
If we can find the door.
我想我找到了
I think I know where it is.
如果这些伤不是玩滑板摔的呢
What if... these aren't from skateboarding?
这孩子玩过PVC炸药管
The kid has been blowing up PVC pipe bombs.
如果炸弹碎片击中他
If he got hit by shrapnel,
身体会将异物包裹起来
the body walls off the foreign object,
因为这些异物是塑料材质
which, because it's plastic,
造影显示不出来
doesn't show up on imaging
于是为细菌滋生提供了温床
and provides a perfect home for bacteria.
抗生素攻击感染部位
Antibiotics attacked the infection,
炸弹碎片破裂开来
causing pieces to break off.
其中一些袭击了肝脏
Some hit the liver.
有一片停留在脑部
One lodged in his brain and dissolved
被福曼碰到的时候消解了
when Foreman touched it.
切开脓肿取出碎片
Once we drain the abscess and remove the shrapnel,
抗生素就会起作用
the antibiotics can do their job.
他会好起来的
He'll be fine.
现在的问题只剩  你要怎么做呢
Which just leaves... What are you gonna do now?
余下的汤我放冰箱里了
I put the rest of the soup in the freezer
留给你下顿吃
so you'll have some for later.
-谢谢你照顾我  -不客气
- Thanks for everything. - Yeah.
-来  -我能行
- Here you go. - I got it.
你会告诉咱妈吗
Are you gonna tell mom?
好让她赶来以她独特的方式照顾你
So she can show up here to take care of you
把你的保姆骂得狗血淋头
by harassing the housekeeper
浴袍贬得一文不值
and criticizing your bathrobe?
算了吧  我看还是过几年再说
Yeah. I think I'm gonna wait a few years.
还有  安全起见
Oh, and I moved your sleeping pills back
我把你的安眠药放回药橱里了
in the medicine cabinet because I just worry.
瑞秋总说药片是糖
Rachel always calls them candy.
你吃了维科丁
You took vicodin.
那晚你来我病房的时候
When you came to my hospital room that night,
正飘飘然呢
you were stoned.
你怎么知道的
How did you know?
我怎么会不知道
How did I not know?
我怎么能自欺欺人数月之久
How did I make myself forget for months
忘记你是瘾君子
that you're an addict?
原来我的潜意识一直在试图提醒我
My subconscious was trying to tell me
你不依靠药物是不可能挺得过这件事的
you could never get through this without drugs.
我只吃这一次
It was a one-time thing.
豪斯  这与药物无关
It's not about the pills, House.
而是这背后的意义
It's about what they mean.
我当时很害怕
I was scared because I thought
因为我以为我女朋友会死
my girlfriend might die.
不
No.
你吃维科丁不是因为恐惧
You don't take vicodin because you're scared.
你吃维科丁是为了逃避痛苦
You take it so you won't feel pain.
你所做过的一切都是为了逃避痛苦
Everything you've ever done is to avoid pain...
你依赖药物  愤世嫉俗
Drugs, sarcasm...
与所有人保持一臂之遥
keeping everybody at arm's length
因为这样就没人能伤到你
so no one can hurt you.
与世界上其他人汲汲寻觅痛苦
As opposed to everyone else in the world
如同寻宝形成鲜明对比吗
who goes looking for pain like it's buried treasure?
有爱即有忧
Pain happens when you care.
要爱一个人
Y... you can't love someone
就要会面对对方的烦恼和恐惧
without making yourself open to their problems, their fears.
而这些正是你不愿意做的
And you're not willing to do that.
我  我是去陪你的
I ca... I came to be with you.
可你没在我身边  那不是真实的你
But you weren't with me, not really.
我想陪你的
I wanted to be.
只想是不够的
That's not enough.
我可以改
I can do better.
我觉得你改不了
I don't think you can.
你会一而再再而三地
You'll choose yourself over everybody else
选择自己  舍弃他人
over and over again,
因为你生而如此
because that's just who you are.
对不起
I'm sorry.
不  不不不  别这样  不要这样
No. No, no, no. Don't. Don't.
我以为我可以的
I thought I could do this.
求你不要这样
Don't. Please don't.
再见  豪斯
Good-bye, House.